Good afternoon Happy holiday to you
Добрый день С праздничком вас
today, thank you
сегодня спасибо
thank you Republic Day
спасибо День республики
Kazakhstan And you already have something like midnight and it
Казахстан А у вас уже типа полночь есть
turns out I’m from the city of Khmelnitsky You’re
получается Я из города Хмельницкий Вы
from Kostanay Kostanay you Russian
откуда Костанай Костанай вы русские
Kazakhs, how do you feel about the fact that ROSI
казахи как относитесь тому что РОСИ у
in general, well, we just keep it neutral neutral
вообще ну нейтрально нейтрально держим
And you study the Kazakh language,
просто А вы казахский язык
I know Well  speak
изучаете знаю Ну говорите
Kazakh in a hundred colloquial
по-казахски сто разговорном
Yes, it’s just that someone there says that they don’t Well, yes,
Да просто кто-то там говорит что не Ну я
well, because I saw this video,
да ну потому что я видел этот ролик
maybe they saw it, yes, you also have on TikTok that a
может видели да у вас тоже в тиктоке что
coach of some kind of martial arts
тренер какой-то единоборств пацанкам
tells the boys that they need to speak not
типа рассказывают что типа нужно не
in Russian  - we saw speaking Kazakh, yes,
по-русски по-казахски говорить видели да
this is generally a [ __ ] And what a
это это вообще это пиздабольство А что
[ __ ] it is Because here everything will be spoken in Russian Well, we
пиздобол сво Потому что тут на русском
need to switch to
всё разговорит Ну так надо переходить на
Kazakh this We, too, in Ukraine
казахский сего У нас тоже в Украине
had a lot of Russian once upon a time for
очень много было русского когда-то по
secular secular
светская светская
studies Who wants it in that language
учёба Кто хочет тот на том языке
speaks not secular - that means
разговаривает не светская - это значит
not religious Well, secular, yes, well,
не религиозная Ну светская да да ну
what is your official language,
государственный язык у вас какой
Kazakh? Well, we teach
государственный казахский Ну мы держим
three languages, well, how does he teach three languages? Yes,
три языка ну как преподает же три языка
I can teach as much as I can Yes, but yes,
Да преподавать мо может сколько Да но да
but it turns out that Kazakh Well, how
но получается что казахский Ну и как бы
should we respect this  the same country and speak
надо уважать эту же страну и говорить на
Kazakh No, well, I’m speaking for myself. I
казахском Нет ну я за себя говорю Я
know, but when you come to a store,
знаю а в магазин когда ты приходишь там
for example, what language do you speak to the
например ты на каком языке говоришь
salesperson? Room in Russian, everything is in Russian,
продавцу рум на русском на все руском
so how are you going to switch to Kazakh,
гово так как же вы будете на казахский
everything will be in Russian
переходить так все на русском будете
basically No
принципиально Нет
Why do your ancestors Kazakhs go over,
зачем Зачем переходи твои предки казахи
this is the language of your
это язык твоих
ancestors if you talk everything in Russian
предков если все разговарить на русском
Why the [ __ ] don’t you say a word? Why
Нахуя чтоб ты слова Нахуя не
the hell then Why the hell would it be in
Понятно Нафига тогда Нафига как будет
Kazakh the equivalent of this
по-казахски аналог этого
word
слова
as it would be Why in Kazakh there’s
как будет Зачем по-казахски
nothing gay, that is, that
ниг не вот гея
is, the point is
есть то есть Дело в том
that the cultural code of every nation is
что культурный Код да каждого народа это
the language So you are turning into Russians,
язык Так вы в русских превращается
you understand, and not into Kazakhs, bad
понимаете а не в казахов плохого
And pho, well, because the war is going on there,
А пхо ну потому что выс там Война идёт
there is no need to involve the Kazakhs
не надо вмешивать казахов
in you, the Kazakhs live in
во вы казахи жите в
Kazakhstan, come on. Even before the war,
Казахстане поди Прим ещ до войны вот
the Latvians in Latvia, like, are switching to  The Latvian is asking
латыши в Латвии типа переходят на Латыш
himself to figure out what you’re
поя у самит разбираться че вы
trying to figure out. I’m not asking the Republic, specifically
лезете Я не у Республики конкретно у
you,
тебя
why I’m
спрашиваю заче меня
room, I’m there in Russia and they believe that the
рум я там Россия и они считают что
northern territories of Kazakhstan are
северные территории Казахстана это
Russian
русская
land, that would be ru So wait what
земля это такна бы ру Так подожди то что
happens, well, Putin also said
получается ну Путин также говорил
Ukraine Donetsk Lugansk is Russia  and
Украина Донецк Луганск это Россия и
took away that it was all his Well, it
забрал что это всё его Ну так а
turns out that you
получается у вас же тоже на севере
also have a lot of people in the north of Kazakhstan too,
Казахстана тоже куча
and that you’re not for whom you
зах и что и ты не Ты за кого
will be for
будешь за
whom for Nazarbayev, who [ __ ] off to the
кого за Назарбаева который Съебал в
Emirates somewhere Yes, look, no, for
Эмираты куда-то Да смотри вот нет вот
example, Putin  there or who will be after
например Путин там или кто будет после
him says that like everything in the northern part of
него говорит что типа всё северной части
Kazakhstan where they speak Russian it
Казахстана где говорят по-русски это
will be the Russian Federation we are holding a
будет Российская Федерация мы проводим
referendum we are
референдум
disconnecting That is, you support this I
отсоединяем То есть ты это поддерживаешь
support It’s
поддерживаю
cool you’re a Kazakh living in
Прикольно ты казах живёшь в
Kazakhstan
Казахстане
but I don’t believe I don’t believe what’s in your
по я не верю Я не верю что у вас в
city  they say in Russian what kind of
городе говорят по-русски что это за
city is Kostanay, a northern city
город такой Костанай северный город
that used to be [ __ ] Russia, which
который раньше был бля Росси который
was called Kustanai through And now
назывался Кустанай через А сейчас
through
через
Kaza and from time immemorial, too, or on this
Каза и спокон веков тоже или на этой
territory like, uh, somehow a tribe on b
территории как ээ как-то плем на б
which was the first in the world to saddle a horse. Let
которое первое в мире оседлали лошадь Да
’s take it  300 years ago Who lived there
вот возьмём 300 лет назад Кто там жил
200 years
200 лет
ago 300 years ago 200 years ago the Kazakhs lived I
назад 300 лет 200 назад казахи жили Я
was born [ __ ] there are no pure Kazakhs
родился бляд нет чистых казахов нету
because the Mongol Ching San conquered and there are
потому что мо Монгол Чинг Сан завоевал и
pure Russians yes there are
а чистый русский есть да вот чистых
no pure Kazakhs but there are pure Russians there are
казахов нет а вот чистые русские прямо
pure Russians there are pure Kazakhs
есть чистые Русские есть чистые казахи
there are also the other 120 there are so then
есть и остальные 120 на есть так то вот
look. If it turns out Russia when it
смотри Если получается Россия когда
came to your Kustanai when the Russians
пришла вот в ваш Кустанай когда русские
came to Kustanai for the first time how many
пришли в Кустанай в первый раз сколько
years
лет
ago
назад
from the very moment they found
само с самого того момента как они нашли
minerals in Well how long is it 100
полезные ископаемы в Ну сколько это 100
years ago 200 years ago  no more than 200 and
лет назад 200 лет назад не больше 200 да
about 900 years ago probably And where 900
где-то 900 лет назад наверное А где 900
years ago everything 1,000 years ago in short BN
лет назад всё 1.000 лет назад короче БН
there in Moscow in toads kva ROSI okay not
там в Москве в жабы ква РОСИ ладно не
Russia USSR so the USSR 100 years ago the
России СССР так СССР вот 100 лет назад
USSR kind of appeared Well, before that the
СССР типа появилась Ну а до этого
Russian Empire came This  you e
Российская империя пришла Это ты е
Now I’ll tell you straight Taras Shevchenko
Сейчас я тебе скажу прямо Тарас Шевченко
still served there somewhere near Orenburg
ещё служил там где-то под оренбургом
now there
сейчас там
oh
э ой
[music]
[музыка]
b so in 1731,
б так в 1731 году
well, 400 Well,
вот ну 400 Ну
300 isn’t even there yet 300 years Ukraine
300 ещё даже нету 300 лет Украина и то
was
дольше была
under Russian rule even longer,
под властью российской
that is  we have been liberated and we are
э то есть мы до мы освободились ти и мы
not saying [ __ ] us Russia but we are
не говорим нахер нам Россия ти что мы
Russia here it turns out to be Russian Well look
Россия тут получается рус Ну смотри
the Russians conquered like yes for 300 years in short
русские завоевали типа да 300 лет короче
they pulled out extracted minerals
вытягивали вытягивали полезные ископаемы
yes you were liberated today
да Вы освободились у вас сегодня День
Republic Day Yes but you start to say
республики Да но ты начинаешь говорить
that this is Russia this is Russia  Damn, what kind of
что это Россия это Россия Блин какая
[ __ ] are you at all I don’t understand for fun you
[__] ти вообще не Поня по приколу
said it for fun You say
говорил вы по приколу Говорите
because we’re
пото
talking from Russia they will come from Russia as militants
говорим из России будут ехать боевиками
like Oh to defend how is he only
типа О вот защищать как это он только в
talking in your direction for fun and in
твою сторону по приколу говорит а в
the other direction we are neutral Because
другую сторону мы нейтрально Потому что
you are starting to express this
ты начинаешь Вот это высказывать
e Impose  we have all this
э Навязывать нам вот это насчёт русских
about the Russians And what, well, what is this trigger for you
всё такое А что ну что это тебя тригер А
Well, look, there’s something wrong with the
ну смотри что-то не так с
Russians That’s exactly what’s wrong with what’s
русскими Вот именно что не так с что не
wrong with the Russians Well, look, they’re talking,
так с русскими Ну ну смотри они разго
here we are talking in Russian Yes,
вот мы разговариваем на русском Да вот
look, they’re 300  about 300 years ago
смотри они 300 лет 300 лет назад
they captured you in Russian talk to
захватили русском разговаривать
you 300 years ago they
вас 300 лет назад
captured you now you were freed in
захватили теперь Вы освободились в де
2009 and gained independence Yes,
году да обрели независимость Да
congratulations to you yes In short, and
поздравляем вас да Во и короче и вы
now you’re like this is the imperial past you’re
сейчас типа вот это имперское прошлое
dragging on like we’re And what we’re going to
тянете типа что мы А что мы будем
say in Russian is the same  so Russian
по-русски говорите это же так русские
territories and so
территории и так
on No, well, this is a thing of the past
дальше Не ну это дело прошлого потому
because the Russian Empire of the USSR sent all the poor
что Российская империя СССР всех бедных
Russians to Kazakhstan Well this is
россиян отправляла Казахстан Ну это
Kazakhstan yes Russia this in the USSR all
Казахстан да Россия этот в СССР всех
Ukrainians nations other nations yes Well
украинцев нации другие нации да Ну
look you know what you say we don’t
смотри вы жете что ты говоришь это мы не
matter Well again  look at
имеем значения Ну ещё раз смотри в
the Constitution in Kazakhstan Open
Казахстане вот Конституцию Открывайте у
your law about the state language, what is
вас закон про государственный язык как
it called? Yes, now SZh is there. It is clearly
это называется Да сейчас СЖ там Чётко
stated that the state language is
сказано что государственный язык
Kazakh.
казахский
Yes, now I’m just Russian, no, I’ve already read
Да сейчас я пря русский нет я уже читал
Russian there at the time
русский там в пор
and another 120
и ещё 120
trailers, it’s definitely Russian that’s not
вагончиков точно русский не
the state language; I’m already someone-  then
государственный меня уже кто-то такое
I already said this, it’s just that the
говорил я уже это прям вот
state language is the
государственным языком является
Kazakh language, that’s
казахский язык
all. The Russian language in Kazakhstan, look, the
всё Вот русский язык в Казахстане смотри
Russian language in Kazakhstan in 2009
русский язык в Казахстане в во дем году
officially lost the status of the
официально утратил статус
state language in the eighty-
государственного языка в восемьдесят
ninth
девятом
year. Even under the
году ещё При
Union, it was
Союзе
clearly
чётко
written, look at this article of the
написано вот смотри статья се
constitution of the Republic of Kazakhstan Yes  in
конституции Республики Казахстан Да в
the country, the state is the Kazakh
стране государством является казахский
language, don’t look, for some reason
язык не смотри вот почему-то вот до нас
you ask us everything, even if our
у нас всё спрашиваешь если даже наши
presidents speak first on New Year’s Day,
президенты на Новый год сначала
well, they congratulate everyone in
разговаривают Ну бля поздравляют всех на
Kazakh and Russian, I’m not the same, look,
казахском и на русском я же не то смотри
I’m not saying that, here he is first  in
я же не то говорю вот он сначала на
Kazakh correctly first in Kazakh
казахском правильно сначала на казахском
and then for people because there are
да вот потом для людей потому что есть
a lot of people who speak Russian
много людей которые говорят на русском
he addresses e in Russian Yes but you
он обращается е на русском Да но вы ж
live like that in Kazakhstan You should speak
так живёте в Казахстане Вы должны на
Russian why there are a lot of you because
русском почему вас много потому что вот
a lot of people resettled you like yes
вас переселяли куча людей типа да
Russify  Russian Yes And so on So
русифицировать русский Да И так дальше
you have to go back to Kazakh,
Вот вы должны возвращаться к казахскому
what’s the problem? It’s your native language
в чём проблема Это же ваш Родной язык
and if you go into a store and say
и если ты зайдёшь и в магазине скажешь
in Kazakh what
на казахском что
will happen, what if the seller here sucks
будет а вдруг продавец у нас хуя
sellers Russian, we’re all about So wait,
продавцов рус у нас все про Так подожди
that is, the Russian seller of Kazakh  doesn’t
то есть русский продавец казахского не
know Knows from afar just like me
знает Знает издалека так же как я
conversation wait then look again it
разговор подожди то смотри ещё раз
turns out in the country Kazakhs must know
получается в стране казахи должны знать
both Kazakh and Russian in order to
и казахский и русский чтобы что-то
buy something, but Russian in Kazakhstan where
купить а русский в Казахстане где
Kazakh is the state language
казахский есть государственный язык
may not know ka I don’t want to know
может не знать ка я не хочу знать
Contact me at  -Russian, yes, how is it
Обращайся ко мне по-русски да как это
so? So, whose country is this?
так Полу так кто чья это страна Русских
We ourselves don’t know, Russians or Kazakhs, that is,
или казахов мы сами не знаем то есть
look, that is, let’s say an American
смотри то есть допустим американец
comes to the store, goes to the shelf,
придёт в магазин подойдёт к полке
takes this product, goes to the cash register, he
возьмёт этот товар пойдёт к касе ему
needs to say Yes, just don’t need to
надо говорить Да просто не надо карту
attach a card, nothing, he can  I can just
приложить ничего он может просто мо
take it and
взять и
go Why the [ __ ] should I know the Kazakh Russian language?
пойти Нахуя знать язык казахский русский
Why should an American who doesn’t know either
Зачем американец который не знает ни
Russian or Kazakh, but you have
русский ни ни казахский А вот у вас что
everything that speaks Ukrainian? You’re
все на украинском разговаривает Вот ты
talking, but look, we mean
разговариваешь да смотри у нас значит
look, we also passed a law.
смотри у нас тоже приняли приняли закон
What about the service sector?  Yes, if
Да что в сфере обслуживания То есть если
you come Yes, the seller must
ты приходишь Да тебе продавец должен
first address you in Ukrainian Yes,
сначала обратиться по-украински Да
only if you are already in some other language Yes, you
только если ты уже на другом языке
contact him, he can
каком-то Да к нему обращаешься он может
then switch to another language and by
тогда перейти на другой язык а по
default Yes, he is the one who invites you to this
умолчанию Да он вин повен инвита это
Ukrainian language and asks for the Ukrainian language
украинскую мову и запыт украинскую мову
that’s all logical for you. And how many
вот и всё это логично вас А сколько у
Nazis are there in your country in general,
вас в стране вообще наци
just like everyone else, a bunch of different people
так же как и у всех куча всяких на нас
came to visit us there, the seller must know all
приехали там продавец должен знать все
the languages ​​or something Everyone who comes should
языки что ли Все кто приезжают должны
know Ukrainian, that’s what
знать украинский вот в том-то и есть
the country is not a seller Look  not a salesman
страна не продавец Смотри не продавец
should know all
должен знать все
languages ​​And everyone who lives should know everything
языки А все кто живут должны знать все
Who comes here should know this language
Кто приезжает должны знать этот язык
that lives here or in English
который тут живут либо на английском
contact if sri I came yes When
обратиться если сри я приезжал да Когда
I was in Austria Yes, I didn’t say I didn’t
я был в Австрии Да я не говорил не
go into the store so give me these
заходил в магазин так дай ты мне эте
eggs  Mozart at all Yes, I didn’t speak, I
яйца Моцарта вобще Да я не говорил я
applied because I don’t know German
обращался поскольку я не знаю немецкий
Yes, I spoke in English Yes in
Да я обращался по-английски Да на
some foreign language Yes, and they didn’t
каком-то иностранном языке Да и и они не
have to know
обязаны были знать
it, we are coming to another country Yes,
его мы приезжаем в другую страну Да
for example, we are coming to Germany in
например мы приезжаем в Германию в
Germany in what  language
Германии на каком языке
they serve Chinese German German
обслуживают китайский немецкий немецкий
here in Poland What language
вот в Польше На каком языке
is served
обслуживают
Polish Yes in the Czech Republic in Czech Yes in
польский Да в Чехии на чешском Да во
France in French in
Франции на французском в
Kazakhstan the aunt speaks Russian because
Казахстане тётка на русском потому что
she doesn’t know Kazakh what’s the problem
она казахского не знает в чём проблема
[ __ ] nothing Why don’t they know
ни в чём бляд А почему они не знают
Kazakh because they don’t  they want because they
казахский потому что не хотят потому что
don’t want That’s exactly what they don’t want. Study we don’t
не хотят Вот именно не хотят Изучи мы не
want this whole state. Well, as a
хотим это всё государство Ну как
state, here’s a grandmother who’s been sitting in prison, she’s
государство вот бабка которая сидит она
been living for 30 years already in independent
живёт 30 лет уже в независимом
Kazakhstan, what’s 3 32 years in
Казахстане сколько 3 32 года в
independent Kazakhstan there was a moment in the
независимом Казахстане был момент в
past, probably three or four centuries ago,
прошлом наверное века три-четыре назад
when they removed  completely Kazakh and then
когда убрали полностью казахский а потом
they returned centuries ago three or four
вернули века три-четыре
years ago Well, these are not centuries Yes, we
назад Ну не века это года Да у нас
actually have a hell of a
вообще [__] не
lot of switches here
то переключились здесь
Yes, a very revealing video Yes,
Да очень показательный ролик да
Kazakhstan has Yes, this is the same problem
Казахстан имеет Да вот такую проблему
as Ukraine Yes, these
как и Украина Да вот эти
soviet metastases of the Russian
совковые метастазы российского мира
Russian world Yes, you understand  What’s the joke
русского Да вы же поняли в чём прикол
when a Kazakh comes to Kazakhstan, where the
когда казах приходит в Казахстане где
national language is the state language,
национальный язык государственный язык
Kazakh, he’s in his native land, so
казахский он на своей родной земле так
he has to switch to a
он должен в магазине переходить на
foreign language in Russian in the store, because
иностранный язык на русский Потому что
grandma
бабка
doesn’t know Kazakh and doesn’t want to know
да не знает казахский и не хочет знать
Kazakh. Yes, but Russian when he comes, yes,
казахский Да а русский когда приходит да
which
которы
is  indigenous to this land Yes, here he is, as
есть коренной на этой земле Да вот он в
a result of this occupation, a
результате этой оккупации там появился
Russian Ukrainian, a Pole, a German appeared there, all
русский украинец поляк немец вот все
other
другие
nations, they are not, in short, that I will speak in
нации они нет короче что я буду
Kazakh, I will speak in Russian, this is
по-казахски я по-русски вот это и есть
this Russian world, yes, that is, they want
этот русский мир да то есть они хотят
everyone to know everything  Russian and everyone
все чтобы все знали русский и все к ним
addressed them in Russian, but they don’t want
обращались по-русски а они не хотят
any languages, and when a Kazakh
никаких языков причём когда казах
comes to Russia,
приезжает в Россию
Moscow,
Москву
what are these guys coming in large numbers there, mastur, and
что там эти понаехали там мастур да как
how they tease like Natsik, these Russians
вот дразнят типа нацики эти русские так
respond like that and they come on, learn Russian. Come on,
отзываются и они давай учи русский Давай
come on with yes. And here  in
то давай с да А тут в
Kazakhstan they don’t want to learn
Казахстане принципиально не хотят учить
Kazakh in principle And in principle they don’t want
казахский И принципиально не хотят
Of course there will be something that yes of course that it will be
Конечно будет такое что да конечно что
that these Russians will be
будет что вот эти [__] будут
promoted there and so we need to
продвигаться там да поэтому надо
look who we have Kazakhs
смотрите кто вот у нас казахи есть
promote this topic What needs to be
продвигайте вот эту тему Что нужно нужно
increased uh let’s say the role of the Kazakh
увеличивать ээ скажем роль казахского
language in  in all spheres, yes, that is, in the
языка во всех сферах да то есть при на
civil service Yes, Doge knowledge of Kazakh And so
госслужбе Да дож знания казахского И так
on, we were slowed down with this and this is
дальше у нас с этим тормозили тормозили
what it resulted in, yes, that’s why it’s
и вот в что оно вылилось да поэтому это
very, very important, subscribe to the
очень-очень важно подпишись на й
Telegram right now, the axis of wine and
Telegram прямо зараз ось вин а
ass is very and very important YouTube
попк це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube
driving us through Scar or new ban and even
загоняя нас через Скар ор ньй бан и дуже
more videos I don’t show people often I don’t
багато вдео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about the stream For this purpose,
показуе информация про стрими Тому для
we need Mali to write an operational link
того щоб ми Мали оперативний звязок
right away and while there in telegra
пишиться прямо зараз а пок там в телегра
okm video sche tezh tsikava and korisna
окм видео ще теж цикава и корисна
information and we will give you trima postiyniy
информация и мы пон вами трима постийний
operational link
оперативный звязок
nezalezhnogo chi show you about it
незалежно того чи покаже вам про це
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава Украине
write
пиши